これより 最終ミッション
未来を司る女神作戦の概要を
説明する
確定した過去を変えずに
結果を変えろ
血まみれで倒れている
牧瀬 紅莉栖と
I will now explain the parameters
それを見た 岡部 倫太郎
of the final mission, Operation Skuld.
その確定した過去を変えずに
結果を変えるのだ
Change the result without changing
the established past.
The past consists of Makise Kurisu,
lying in a bloody pool,
父さん そこのドライバー 取って
and Okabe Rintarou seeing her there.
Change the past without changing that.
だから ｢父さん｣って…
いいから 早く！
やっぱり あと１往復が限界かな
過去に行って 戻ってくる
そのくらいの燃料しか残ってない
Dad, pass me that screwdriver.
Why are you calling me "Dad"?
お前がいた未来には
帰れないということか
Just do it...
As I thought. We only get one more trip.
もともと 戻る気がなかった
We don't have enough fuel for more than
one trip to the past and back.
こっちで世界線を変えて
未来が変われば
戻る必要は なかったから
So you won't be able to return to the future?
ただ…
I never planned to.
もし 変えることができなければ
By changing the world line here,
あたしは
ここで生きていくことになる
thus changing the future, I won't need to go back.
ずっと後悔したまま
But...
If I fail to change it, I'll have to stay here...
何をバカなことを言っている
Regretting it, forever.
おじさん…
おじさんではない
我が名は 鳳凰院 凶真
Don't be stupid!
狂気の
マッドサイエンティストにして
世界の支配構造を破壊する男
Uncle...
I'm not your uncle.
失敗など あり得ん
I am Hououin Kyouma, mad scientist,
分かった 信じるよ
and the man who will destroy
the world's ruling structure.
Failure is not an option...
これより 未来を司る女神作戦を
実行に移す！ 時は 来たれり！
Got it. I believe you.
We commence Operation Skuld...
The time is now!
な～い どこだ！
Where is it?
ここら辺に
置いてあったはずなのだが…
I know it was around here somewhere...
Achievement Point
｢時は 来たれり！｣ キリッ！
He made me LOL when he said, "The time is now,"
…とかしといて 忘れ物して
ラボに戻ってる件について
but immediately had to run to the lab
because he forgot something.
早くしてよ？
タイムマシン あんまり 長い間
Hurry up!
We can't leave the time machine
there for too long...
あそこに置いとくわけには
いかないんだから
あ～ もう ここ… ここ…
うん？
サイリウム･セーバー？
The Cyalume Saber?
そんなもん 何するん？
What are you going to do with that?
重要なのは この先端に
仕掛けられている 血のり
The sticky red liquid of its core is the key.
へえ そんなのあったんだ！
Huh? I didn't know that was there.
なるほど それを
牧瀬 紅莉栖の血に見せるわけだね
I understand.
You plan to substitute it for Makise Kurisu's blood.
いかにも
Exactly.
７月28日の俺が
On July 28th, if I see
血のりの上で 気を失って
倒れているｸﾘｽﾃｨｰﾅを発見すれば
an unconscious Christina, lying in a pool of blood,
確定した過去は 変わらない
the past won't change.
それが 未来を司る女神作戦の
意味するところ
That is the idea behind Operation Skuld.
確かに 理屈は合ってるけれど…
I guess it makes sense, but...
でも なんか 単純すぎねえ？
15年後のオカリンは
Doesn't it seem a little too easy?
Future Okarin sounded like a
larger secret was at work here.
もっと でかい秘密がありそうな
感じで 話していたように思われ
フフフフ… 鳳凰院 凶真は
Hououin Kyouma speaks ever more dramatically,
作戦が 単純であればあるほど
大げさに言う男だ
when a plan is simple.
フフフフ… バカめ
The fool...
既に 貴様のやり方は
すべて 見抜いているのだ！
I see through his schemes!
感心していいところなのかな？
I don't know whether to be impressed or not...
全俺が泣いた
ねえ…
Mad scientist fail.
オカリン？
Hey...
Okarin?
あっ？
紅莉栖さんって
ここに座ってなかった？
Did that Kurisu-san person sit here?
オカリンと…
まゆり…
With you?
Mayuri...
ダル君と
いつも 一生懸命 話してて
She'd get really excited and talk to Daru-kun.
まゆしぃは よく分からないけど
なんか夢中で話してて
And Mayushii wouldn't really understand,
but they were having lots of fun.
オカリンと紅莉栖さんは
よくケンカするんだけど
And you two fought constantly,
きっと とっても仲良くて…
but really, you were good friends.
まゆ氏 何 言っておるん？
Mayushii, what are you talking about?
牧瀬 紅莉栖って 天才科学者だお
Makise Kurisu is a scientific genius...
こんなラボに 来るはずないって
She'd never come to a lab like this.
うん 変だよね…
It's weird, right?
夢なのかな？
Was it a dream?
もしかして
この子にも運命探知が？
Maybe she possesses the Reading Steiner, also?
いや そんな力はない
No, she doesn't.
でも どこかで覚えてるんだ
But somewhere inside, she remembers
別の世界線であったことを
誰でも 心のどこかで
what happened in the other world lines.
Everyone does, somewhere in their hearts.
紅莉栖は まゆりを助けるために
全力を尽くしてくれた
Kurisu did everything she could to save Mayuri.
まゆりが いや 俺たちが
今 ここに立っているのは
Mayuri... No, all of us can be here now
紅莉栖のおかげなんだ
ええ？
because of Kurisu.
ねえ オカリン？
Hey, Okarin? Do you like Kurisu-san?
紅莉栖さんのこと 好き？
あっ…
クリスティーナは 俺の助手であり
Christina is my assistant, my dear friend,
大切な仲間であり
そして 特別な存在だ
and very special to me.
そっか
I understand.
それに あいつが
俺に ほれているという事情もある
And she's in love with me, too.
ウソ！ まさかのリア充展開…
No way! Okarin gets a real girlfriend?
じゃあ 絶対 助けなきゃ
何があっても
Then, you have to save her,
no matter what.
あっ…
You must save her!
絶対 助けなきゃ！
ああ
Yeah.
うん！
Yup.
ん～…
きっと 帰ってきてね
紅莉栖さんを連れて
Be sure to bring her back!
当たり前だ！
あっ あの！
I will.
Hey, um... Miss Amane...
阿万音氏
僕の娘っていうのが
本当だとすると
If you're really my daughter,
僕の嫁は？
who was my bride?
それは 秘密にしておく
またか
I'll keep that a secret.
Again?
うん？
ええ？
Let's go!
行くぞ！
さっきと
まったく同時刻に到達できた
We've managed to arrive at
exactly the same time as before.
後は おじさん次第だよ
The rest is up to you.
分かってる
サイリウム･セーバーを
Understood.
Just leave the Cyalume Saber where I asked you to.
例の場所に 置いといてくれ
任せて！
On it.
確定した過去を変えずに
結果を変える
Change the result without changing
the established past...
そのためには…
For that to work...
まずは ここだ
...this is where I begin.
因果関係は 分からない
I don't know the overall effect,
だが ここで 俺が
メタルうーぱを出してしまえば
but if I get the metal Upa here,
あの封筒に
金属が紛れ込む可能性は 低くなる
it diminishes the odds of
any metal ending up in that folder.
やはり
I thought so.
はっ…
このシリーズ
あんまり残ってないのに
There aren't many left of this series,
まゆしぃは 百円玉を
切らしちゃっているのです
and Mayushii's out of hundred-yen coins!
甘ったれるな まゆり
Don't be a spoiled little girl, Mayuri.
たとえ 幼なじみであっても
Even if I've known you since we were kids,
I'm not lending you money.
金は 貸さん
ええ～！
フフフ… お前に 今
人生の厳しさを教えてやろう
I'll teach you how harsh life can be...
あ…
It's an Upa!
うーぱだよ！
レアなのか？
Is it rare?
レアじゃないけどね
すごく かわいいでしょ？
It's not rare, but isn't it cute?
よし 次！
Okay, next...
あっ あ… すみません
I'm sorry!
く… 紅莉栖？
Kurisu.
えっ？ どうして 私の名前を？
How do you know my name?
どこかで お会いしましたっけ？
Have we met somewhere before?
紅莉栖…
聞いてます？ あっ
Kurisu...
Are you listening—
何なんです？
質問に 答えてください！
What's wrong with you?
Answer me.
俺は…
I...
えっ？
俺は お前を…
I'm going to save you.
助ける！
これより ８階ホールにて
中鉢博士の会見が開かれます
Professor Nakabachi's press conference
will now begin in the 8th Floor Hall.
待って… 待ちなさい！
Wait!
Wait a second!
あ…
まさか 自分で自分を
演じることになるとはな
I never imagined I'd have to
pretend to be myself.
まゆりの落とした うーぱを
紅莉栖が拾っていたのか！
Kurisu picked up the Upa that Mayuri dropped?
Mayushii
だが
うーぱが金属でなくなった以上
But now that it's no longer metal,
中鉢の封筒は 放っておいても
飛行機の事故で焼けるはず
that folder will burn in the airplane accident.
後は 中鉢を追い払い
All that's left is getting rid of Nakabachi,
隙を見て
紅莉栖を気絶させれば…
and finding a chance to knock out Kurisu.
うっ…
なっ！
血のりが固まってる!?
The liquid dried up?
そうか 長い間
血のり部分は使わずにいたから
That's right!
I haven't used it for such a long time,
空気に触れて 凝固し… あっ！
air got in and dried out the liquid...
何の用だ？
What do you want?
Daddy, I wanted you to read this.
考えろ 考えるんだ
Think...
Think!
何かあるはずだ 何か！
There must be something...
Something!
考えろ…
Getting rid of Nakabachi won't be difficult.
中鉢を追い払うのは
難しいことじゃない
問題は 血のりだ
But the blood's problematic.
血のりの
代わりになるものさえあれば…
If there were just something
I could substitute...
黙れ！
ああっ！
Shut up!
よくも 盗むなどと！
How dare you call it stealing?
そうだ！
That's it!
やめろ！
はっ！
Stop!
誰だ 貴様は！
Who are you?
ハハハハ…
混沌を望み
世界の支配構造を破壊する者
A man who desires chaos...
One who will reset the world's ruling structure...
そして…
And the man who will destroy your ambitions.
お前の野望を 打ち砕く者！
聞きたいか？
Would you like to know my name?
我が名は…
I am...
鳳凰院…
Hououin Kyouma!
凶真！
何を 訳の分からないことを…
What are you talking about?
お前 さっきのガキだな？
You're that kid!
なるほど… そういうことか
I get it.
So that's how it is.
貴様ら 示し合わせて
You worked together,
to ruin my press conference...
私の会見を
台なしにしようとしたんだな？
フフフ… そうか そういうことか
I see... So that's it.
フフッ フフフフ…
パパ！
Daddy...
逃げて！
断る！
Run!
No!
えっ？
どうした！
What's wrong?
そのナイフは
何のために持っているんだ？
Why did you bring that knife?
ぐっ なんだと！
What did you say?
Are you scared?
ポーズだけか？
この 神に等しい力を持つ俺に
恐れをなしたか？
Do my godlike powers terrify you?
くっ… ふ ふざけるな！
D-Don't insult me!
さあ どうした？
Come on, you're shaking.
震えているぞ 怖いのか？
Are you scared?
どこまで
この私を愚弄するつもりだ！
How long will you insult me?
結局 貴様は その程度の男なのだ
Ultimately, you're just a small, pathetic man.
A man too small to enjoy his
own daughter's talent couldn't kill me.
実の娘の有能さを喜べないなど
貴様には
この俺を 殺すことはできない！
Anyway, I don't have too many J-books,
but I'll take a look.
Never!
絶対に… 絶対にな！
Ever!
あっ あ…
はあ はあ…
そ そんな…
N-No way...
はあ… はあ…
くっ う…
ううっ あ…
ウソ ウソ…
No...
This can't be happening.
ハハッ ざ ざまあみろ…
Th-That's what you get...
落ち着け… あと… 少し！
Calm down.
Almost there...
ああっ はあ はあ…
くっ ふう…
くっ はあ はあ…
よ… よくも…
How dare you...
I'll kill you...
殺して…
I'll kill you!
殺してやる！
うう…！
はあ はあ…
ああっ！
ただで済むと思うな！
You won't get away with this!
ああっ はあ…
はっ！ あ ああ…
ああ！
はあ はあ はあ…
う… う 動いちゃダメ！
D-Don't move!
よ 横になって！
今 救急車を呼ぶから！
Lie down. I'll call an ambulance.
はあ はあ… も もしもし？
Hello?
救急ですか？
すぐ来てほしいんです！
Is this emergency services?
I need someone here now!
俺は…
I...
言っただろ…？
俺は お前を…
I told you...
助ける！
うん？ あっ…
I'm going to save you.
はあ はあ ああ…
はあ はあ… うっ…
うっ く…
フッ…
くっ…
うっ うあ～！
これは… 間違いなく俺が見た
This is, without doubt,
紅莉栖だ…
the Kurisu I saw.
Uncle...
おじさん…
さよなら…
Goodbye.
あっ… 待て
えっ？
Wait...
Could you just wait a minute?
ちょっとだけ 待ってくれないか…
そんなこと
している場合じゃないよ！
We don't have time!
おじさん このままじゃ…
You'll bleed out...
Please.
頼む…
おい 誰か いるのか？
Hey... Is someone there?
頑張れよ…
Good luck.
You're about to begin the longest,
これから始まるのは
人生で一番 長く
一番 大切な３週間だ
most important three weeks of your life.
もう… むちゃし過ぎだよ！
バカにも程がある！
You went too far!
You idiot.
バカとは なんだ
計画どおりだろ…
What do you mean by idiot?
The plan succeeded...
簡単な止血しかしてないから
All I can do is stop the bleeding.
戻ったら すぐに 病院 行ってね
When we get back, you need a hospital.
きついと思うけど
なんとか耐えてね
This will be hard, but try to hang on.
いくよ
Here we go.
ううっ うう… うっ
これは…
This is...
Yeah.
運命石の扉は 誰も知らない世界線
No one knows what will happen
in the Steins Gate world line.
鈴羽？
Suzuha...
でも おじさんの理論が正しければ
But if your theory is correct, the paper will burn,
so the time machine race won't come to pass.
論文は焼け
タイムマシン開発競争は起きず
第三次世界大戦も起こらない
Neither will World War III.
あたしは
一緒にいることは できない
I can't stay with you.
So I'll say thank you now.
だから 先に お礼を言っておくね
Thank you.
ありがとう
また 会おうね ７年後に
I'll see you in seven years.
To Okarin
For Okabe
Rintarou-sama
う～んしょ う～んしょ
う～んしょ！
Okabe Rintarou-sama
オカリ～ン！ あっ？
Okarin!
あれ？
That paper would have altered mankind's future...
人類の未来に…
It was a paper for constructing a time machine!
タイムマシンに関わる
重大な論文が…
燃えてしまったんだ！
And it's gone... Burned up!
His words were unclear,
…などと
意味不明であり ロシア政府は
and the Russian government plans to deny...
亡命を受け入れない方針…
Okarin was here, Ruka-kun?
るか君！
オカリンが来たって？
入れ違えに
なっちゃった…
I missed him!
あっ その時…
When he came by...
うん？
This badge identifies you as Lab Member #006.
ラボメンNo.006の証しだ
えっ？ 僕 いつ ラボメンに？
When did I become a lab member?
その記憶は
あるいは前世まで
Those memories may rest in your other life.
さかのぼるかも
しれんな
へえ～ 何だろう？ この文字
What are these characters?
凶真？
Kyouma?
He was just here.
さっきまでいたニャン
I knew it.
やっぱり？ ﾌｪﾘｽちゃん
何か もらわなかった？
Did you get something, Feyris-chan?
うん？ そういえば…
Now that you mention it...
This badge is for Lab Member #007.
ラボメンNo.007のピンバッチだ
助けがほしいときは
それを握りしめ
When you desire my aid, hold the badge and say,
｢ラ･ヨーダ･スタセッラ｣と
唱えるがいい
"La Yohda Stasella."
ほお～
ああ？ 岡部なら
さっきまで ここにいたのによ
Okabe was just here.
Mayuri-oneechan!
まゆりおねえちゃん！
トゥットゥル－ 綯ちゃん… と？
Nae-chan!
ああ 今日から ここで
She'll be working here, from now on.
バイトすることになった…
I'm Kiryuu Moeka.
桐生萌郁です…
綯が転んだところを
助けてもらってな
She helped Nae after she fell down.
She said she didn't have a job,
ちょうど
仕事もないっつうから
so she'll be working here.
ウチで働いてもらうことになった
I'm Shiina Mayuri.
椎名
まゆりです！
大人気だな
She's really popular.
Okabe started hitting on her
the minute he saw her.
岡部の野郎も あんなに
ナンパしやがってよ～
いつでも
ラボを訪れるといい
Visit the lab whenever you like.
あ…
あの… ありがとう
Um...
Thank you.
トゥットゥル－！
おかえリン！
Welcome back-arin!
｢おかえり｣と｢オカリン｣を
合体させたん？
Did you combine "welcome back" and "okarin"?
うん！ オカリンは？
Yup!
Where's Okarin?
うん
ちょっと買い物 行ってくるって
He said he was going shopping.
I see...
そっか～ ああ！
うん？
These?
あ これ？
ラボメンの証しだってさ
He said they're lab member badges.
Lab Member #002 and #003!
ラボメンNo.002と003！
When did we get so many lab members?
いつの間に ラボメン
そんなに増えたん？
He said they go up to #008.
008まであるって言ってたけど…
Okarin's "O."
Ｏは オカリンでしょ？
椎名 橋田 漆原…
Shiina. Hashida. Urushibara. Feyris...
フェリス… うん？
ＭとＫとＡって？
Who are "M" and "K" and "A"?
Dunno.
さあ… あ あと もう１個
He had another one that he put in a box.
箱の中に しまっていったお
Lab Member #008 will arrive in seven years.
ラボメンNo.008は ７年後に現れる
また 妄想っすか？
More fantasies?
It's an inevitable future.
必然だ ダルのな
Your inevitable future.
Mine?
僕の？
Seven years...
７年後…
It'll be fun.
楽しみだな～
どんなラボメンなんだろ？
Who do you think it'll be?
Seven years... I can't imagine.
７年後って… 想像もできないお
But I don't think the lab will change.
でもね ラボは変わらないと思うよ
No matter how many years go by.
何年たっても ずっと…
お前は 今 どこにいるのだろう
Where are you now?
アメリカの研究機関で
論文を書いているだろうか
Are you writing a paper
in an American research lab?
Are you working all night on some experiment?
確かめたいことがあって
徹夜で実験をしているだろうか
もしかしたら 父のことで
まだ 悩んでいるかもしれない
You may still be thinking of your father.
俺と過ごした３週間を
お前は 覚えていない
You don't remember the three weeks
we spent together.
But that's okay.
だが それでいい
Right now, you're breathing, speaking,
お前が 今 どこかで
息をして 声を出して
thinking your hardest about something.
何かを一生懸命 考えている
それで 十分だ
That's enough.
You're watching the same world I am,
俺と同じ世界を
未来が
まだ分からない この世界を
this world with its unknown future.
どこかで一緒に見ているのだから
I finally found you...
やっと… 会えた！
I was looking for you.
あなたを捜していたんです
I wanted to thank you for saving me.
助けてくれた お礼を言いたくて
あ…
It's me.
俺だ なぜ 彼女がここにいる？
Why is she here?
なに？ 俺が守れだと？
What?
Because I protected her?
You're flattering me...
やれやれ
勝手なことを言ってくれる
まあ いい
Well, if that's its choice.
それが 選択だというのなら
エル･プサイ･コングルゥ
El Psy Congroo.
El Psy?
エル･プサイ…？
We meet again, Christina!
また会えたな クリスティーナ！
I told you I'm not Christina,
and I'm not your assistant...
いや だから 私は
ｸﾘｽﾃｨｰﾅでも 助手でもないと…
あっ… あれ？
Welcome, my assistant, Makise Kurisu...
ようこそ 我が助手
牧瀬 紅莉栖 いや クリスティーナ
No, Christina.
No one knows what the future holds.
未来のことは 誰にも分からない
だからこそ
That's why its potential is infinite,
この再会が意味するように
just as this meeting demonstrates.
無限の可能性があるんだ
This is the choice of Steins Gate.
これが 運命石の扉の選択だよ
はい ２
いち にっ！
マツタケ発見
3000ドルもらう
おー すごいな 悠斗
はい 3000 よいしょ
イェーイ 次はパパの番
ほい
おーっ
おお 給料日だぁ
銀行マンだから3000ドルです
はい
やっぱ ありがたいね 給料は
駄目だったんですか？
この前の面接